# **Shubhra Maithil**

Audubon, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Shubhra-Maithil/18b48aad65b7bc39

To work at the position of software engineer and contribute to the organization by using my skills in designing, programming and development. To acquire expertise in handling projects successfully under minimum supervision.

WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Software Developer**

Appin Software Solutions - Jabalpur, Madhya Pradesh - June 2009 to Present

from June 2009. After completing the training for six months, I was given the position of a junior software engineer. I am an applications specialist and in this span of 1.5 years I have developed applications for different projects. It included video games, business operations software, e-learning, etc.

### **Junior Software Engineer**

Appin Software Solutions - June 2009 to December 2011

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Participate in meetings with the seniors to learn about the project specifications and client's expectations for the software
- Deal with different clients such as gaming industry, banking firms, manufacturing units and get a detailed idea about their business nature and requirements
- Convert the business requirements into specifications for applications and develop programming codes for the applications
- Program the system as planned and test the functioning of the system. Make sure the project objectives are met duly.
- Debug the systems to remove any virus threat
- Meet the clients, the industrial heads, and ensure that the system controls the manufacturing assembly as intended by the client. Check and eliminate any possibility of failure or malfunctioning

### Trainee Software Engineer

Appin Software Solutions - June 2009 to December 2009

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Provide online and desk support to the end users and respond to their queries
- Observe the work of the seniors and provide suggestions for developing software
- Use the software and test its performance against the performance targets
- Coordinate with technical authors to write user guides and technical specifications
- Develop codes for program and get them reviewed from the seniors
- Remove the minor program bugs and perform other troubleshooting functions

**EDUCATION** 

#### **MCA**

IGNOU 2011

#### **BCA** in Medical

Govt.Women Polytechnic

## EXAM/

UNIVERSITY / BOARD

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

## SOFTWARE PROFICIENCY

Languages C, C++, Visual Basic, VB.net, ASP.net, Oracle, PL/SQL

Database Oracle 9i, MS-SQL

Operating Systems Windows 98, 2000, XP

Web Designing JAVA SCRIPT, HTML, XML, CSS, VB.net, ASP.net

 $Development\,Methodology\,Awareness\,Object\,Oriented\,Programming,\,Networking,\,Software\,Testing,\,Softwar$ 

Development Life Cycle, Data Mining & ERP

## PERSONAL SKILLS

- Comprehensive problem solving abilities.
- Willingness to learn team facilitator hard worker.
- Determined to learn with practical approach
- Enthusiastic and can produce results under deadline constraints
- Team Work
- Good Communication skill